Dima Tolmachev

Software developer

Details

Currently located in Tbilisi, Georgia

Phone:

+995 599 00 49 19

Fmail.

dima.tolmachev@outlook.com

Telegram:

@dimatolmachev

Personal site:

https://dimatolmachev.me/

Skills

TypeScript
React.js / Next.js
Redux / Mobx
Node.js, express.js
Webpack
Python, Flask
PostgreSQL / non-relational DBs
Linux OS
CI/CD
Git
Docker

Soft skills

Analytical skills Problem solving Attention to detail Work ethic Adaptability

Languages

Russian, native English, intermediate Czech, intermediate

References

Nikita Gorbukhov from Metrica Agency

Telegram: @nikitabmx Email: nekitenzo@gmail.com

Tolmachev Alexey from Legion-it

Telegram: @BA_Aleksey Email: gregorthedark@gmail.com

Profile

Young and talented software developer with a history of leading IT projects and engineering different types of web services.

I have been both employed and worked on my own IT projects. I also have experience of over 3 years of commercial development.

I am looking for a challenging position that will allow me to fulfill my potential and contribute to my future employer's success.

Experience

I am positioning myself as a web developer, mainly frontend. Preferred programming languages are TypeScript & JavaScript (ES6 specification).

I have experience with a wide range of different frameworks. I am also keen about new technologies, but my main stack is Express JS for server-side development and React JS for SPA frontend.

Employment history

Full-stack developer at Metrica Agency

May 2022 - Present. Moscow, Russia (remote)

Responsibilities:

- 1. Development SPA & SSR applications.
- 2. Writing customized unit tests.
- 3. Code reviews.

Technology stack:

- Typescript
- Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB
- React.js + Next.js, Mobx

Software Developer at Tokenizer

January 2022 – August 2022. Moscow, Russia (remote)

Responsibilities:

- 1. Scaling desktop application for automated checkouts on ecommerce sites and NFT minting.
- 2. Writing technical documentation.

Technology stack:

- JavaScript and Python metaprogramming
- RPC interaction: Ethereum, Solana, Cardano

Leading Software developer at Quasar Alpha Group

September 2021 – May 2022. Moscow, Russia (remote)

Responsibilities

- 1. Maintaining and scaling the renewal subscription system (recurring payments in cryptocurrency).
- 2. Communication with customers and developing project roadmap according to their desires.
- 3. Team management, tasks distribution.
- 4. Code reviews.
- 5. Writing web scrappers and CRMs.
- 6. Writing discord bots.

Technology stack:

- TypeScript
- Node.js, Express.js, Discord.js
- Python + Flask, Discord.py
- PostgreSQL
- RPC interaction: Solana, Ethereum, Tron, Binance Smart Chain

Co-founder, tech leader at Degosh

January 2021 – July 2022. Moscow, Russia (remote)

Responsibilities:

- 1. Build backend and frontend architecture.
- 2. Reverse engineering, work with captcha and access tokens, TLS servers.
- 3. Writing checkout automation bots: supreme, adidas/yeezy, Binance NFT.
- 4. Writing and scaling CRM for licenses keys, renewal dates and payments.

Technology stack:

- JavaScript, Angular.js
- Node.js, Express.js, Discord.js
- MongoDB
- Webpack

Web developer at Legion-it

June 2019 – October 2020. Moscow, Russia

Responsibilities:

- 1. Developing ecommerce web sites
- 2. Developing landing pages

Technology stack:

- Figma
- WordPress
- Ecwid
- HTML, CSS
- JavaScript, jQuery

Education

Charles university, FSc

Prague, Czech Republic

I was accepted as a student, however due to the geopolitical situation in Russia, my studies are on hold.

School 508

Moscow, Russia

Program of in-depth study of physics and mathematics. Graduated in May 2020.